# Prasilla Devi Manchem Software Development Engineer

 ♥ Hyderabad
 ★ prasillamanchem@gmail.com
 ★ 7013135755
 ♠ prasilla487

in prasillamanchem

### **Profile**

A Backend Developer with 3.5+ years of experience in Nodejs, Python, Django, Expressjs, SqlServer along with other tools and technologies. Responsibilities involved in finding the quick Solutions for R&D Tasks, and the end to end development

# **Professional Experience**

# Software Development Engineer

Dhan AI 🛮

2020/08 - present | Hyderabad

- Designed and Implemented Rest APIs with Node JS, Express, Typescript and Yarn Workspaces.
- Designed, Managed, optimized, and updated MSSQL databases as necessary.
- Designed and developed application by processing realtime data using Kafka, Redis
- Implemented Single Sign On authentication Using Azure B2C, solved the complex scenarios by implementing custom policies
- Explored and implemented Azure libraries, BotBuilderJs , AzureStorages, AzureB2C, AzureKnowledgeBases, PowerBi module, Azure CI/CD.
- Finding quick solutions in R&D and making development quick. Unit Testing with jest and Task estimations.
- Explored to Electronic Health Record standard FHIR, EPIC, Cernor
- Responsibility of deploying the application under Linux environments. Good knowledge on configuring reverse proxy with Nginx.
- Led Backend development team as Subject Matter Expert and primary point-of-contact for the team.

#### **Software Engineer**

Zebi Data India pvt. Ltd

2019/05 - 2020/07 | Hyderabad

• Coordinated with team on Creating Web Applications with Django and Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the website using the Python, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.

# **Python Developer**

Energetic info solutions

2018/07 - 2019/04 | Hyderabad

• Handled functionality in integration project of ServiceNow and Zendesk systems. Implemented integration with python along with DB queries

## **Education**

# **Computer Science and Engineering**

RGUKT IIIT Nuzvidu 2014/06 - 2018/04

**8.3GPA** 

#### **Skills**

- TypeScript , JavaScript , Node JS
- Python, Django
- ExpressJS, NPM, Yarn, Yarn Workspaces, Typeorm
- MSSQL, MySQL
- · Kafka, Redis
- Git, Jira, Docker, Azure, Swagger

## **Projects**

## **Ziply Customer Notifications**

2021/12 - present

- Ziply Customer Notifications (ZCN) is a service management module that enables Ziply to send notifications to a specific group of customers based on certain "input" events.
- Technology stack: Node JS, Typescript, Kafka, Redis, Mssql, Sendgrid, Twilio, ELK stack, Nginx, Docker

#### **Patient Enrollment Forms**

2021/07 - 2021/12

- Forms for healthcare pharma brands in eliminating their paper work by making signable forms and accessible to bothe patients as well as healthcare providers.
- Technology Stack: Node JS, Typescript, Mssql, SFTP.

## **Patient Engagement Platform**

2020/09 - 2021/05

- Patient engagement platform is designed to provide Chatbots within days of time where these chatbots are involved in patinets journey thoughout the disease of patinet is reolved.
- Technology Stack: Node JS, Typescript, Mssql, Azure B2C, Azure Storage, Azure QnaMaker, BotbuilderJs, Typeorm.